As you might imagine, a lot goes into designing
你也许能够想象 设计机器人需要大量工作
a robot even if it's a virtual robot rather than a real one.
即使是虚拟机器人 而不是真实的机器人也如此
To make it possible for us to use turtle robots in Python,
为了使我们能够在 Python 中使用 turtle 机器人
somebody had to write a bunch of code about turtles,
开发者必须编写大量关于 turtle 的代码
and here it is.
这些就是 turtle 代码
This code makes it possible for us to create
这些代码使我们能够创建 turtle 对象
a turtle object and use simple instructions to have it draw things on the screen.
并通过简单的指令使其能够在屏幕上绘制图形
Now, that's a lot of code.
这段代码很长
This is actually something you'll see a lot of in programming.
你在编程过程中经常会见到大段代码
Someone will write some useful code in a file and then share that file
有人会在文件中编写一些有用的代码并分享该文件
so everyone can use it and not have to write that same code over again themselves.
使所有人都能使用这些代码 无需自己重复编写相同的代码
In Python, these collections of useful code are called modules.
在 Python 中 这些有用代码集合称为模块
In this case, we've made use of the turtle module.
在我们的演示中 我们使用了 turtle 模块
There are all kinds of other useful modules out there as well,
Python 中还有很多其他实用的模块
such as the math module,
例如 math 模块
which has a bunch of code to help you do useful calculations.
其中包含大量执行计算的代码
You know, there are a lot of modules out there,
模块有很多种
and if we put all of those files of code into every program we write,
如果将所有这些文件都放到我们编写的每个程序中
it would slow those programs down a lot.
将会大大降低程序的运行速度
So instead we tell Python when there's
因此 当我们要在程序中使用特定的模块时
a specific module that we want to use in our program.
我们会告诉 Python 该模块
We do that by importing the module.
方法是导入模块
That's what this first line of code import turtle is all about.
这就是第一行代码 import turtle 的作用
That's how we tell Python that we want to do things with turtles in
我们通过这种方式告诉 Python 我们想要在此程序中
this program and we will therefore need access to the code that's in the turtle module.
使用 turtle 执行操作 因此需要访问 turtle 模块中的代码
Once we've imported the turtle module,
导入 turtle 模块后
it's as if all the code we're a part of
就好像所有这些代码都是程序本身的一部分一样
our own program and we can access it to do things with turtles.
我们可以访问这些代码并对 turtle 执行操作
For example, let's take another look at this line, Amy equals turtle.Turtle.
例如 再看一眼这行代码 amy = turtle.Turtle()
Remember, turtle.Turtle is the code that
记住 turtle.Turtle 会在计算机内存中
creates a new turtle object in the computer's memory.
创建一个新的 turtle 对象
Notice how it starts with the name of the module that we need to use,
注意开头是我们要使用的模块的名称
turtle, and then there's a dot.
然后是点
This dot is telling Python to look inside
这个点告诉 Python 在 turtle 模块中查找
the turtle module for some code that is called turtle and run that code.
叫做 turtle 的代码并运行该代码
So it saying run the turtle code that is inside the turtle module,
表示运行 turtle 模块中的 turtle 代码
and it's that code that creates the new turtle object.
正是这段代码创建了新的 turtle 对象
Now once the turtle object has been created,
创建好 turtle 对象后
we can give that turtle instructions such as amy.forward100 or amy.right90.
我们可以向该 turtle 发出指令 例如 amy.forward(100) 或 amy.right(90)
An important thing to understand about these lines is that they're
对于这几行代码需要注意的重要事项是
actually referencing code that is hidden away somewhere else.
它们实际上引用了隐藏在其他位置的代码
Specifically, these lines are referring to code that is inside that turtle module.
具体而言 这几行代码引用的是 turtle 模块内的代码
In that module, there's a block of code that
在该模块中
has instructions for getting the turtle to go forward,
有一个代码块包含了让 turtle 向前移动的指令
and there's another block of code that has the instructions for getting it to turn right.
另一个代码块包含了让 turtle 右转的指令
So, we have these blocks of code that have instructions for making the turtle
这些代码块具有让 turtle 执行不同操作的指令
do different things but these blocks of code don't do anything by themselves,
但是它们本身不执行任何操作
they just sit there waiting to be used.
只是等着被使用
When we run a line of code like amy.forward100,
当我们运行像 amy.forward(100) 这样的代码行时
we are telling Python to find this block of code
我们告诉 Python 查找名称为 forward 的这个代码块
that has the name forward and run that code.
并运行该代码块
In Python, these blocks of code are referred to as methods and we would refer to
在 Python 中 这些代码块称为方法
lines like amy.forward100 and amy.right90 as method calls.
我们将 amy.forward(100) 和 amy.right(90) 等称为方法调用
When we run these lines,
运行这两行代码时
we are calling the forward and write methods that are in the turtle module.
我们在调用 turtle 模块中的 forward 和 right 方法
Amy.coloryellow is another example of a method call and it
amy.color("yellow") 是另一个方法调用示例
is of course calling the block of code named color that is inside the turtle module.
当然 它调用的是 turtle 模块中叫做 color 的代码块
Notice that these method calls always have the name of the method followed by
注意 这些方法调用始终具有方法名称
parentheses and we can put some input inside
然后是小括号 我们可以在括号里放入输入
the parentheses that Python will use when it runs the method.
Python 在运行方法时将使用这些输入
So when we call the forward method,
当我们调用 forward 方法时
it needs to know how much we want the turtle to move forward.
它需要知道我们希望 turtle 向前移动多少个像素
So, here we're using the number 100 to tell it the number of pixels to move forward.
我们使用数字 100 表示向前移动的像素数量
When we call the write method,
当我们调用 right 方法时
it needs input so that it knows how many degrees the turtle should turn.
需要提供一个输入 从而知道应该转多少度
And when we call the color method,
调用 color 方法时
it needs input like yellow or blue.
需要 yellow 或 blue 这样的输入
If methods seem a little mysterious at this point,
如果目前你觉得方法很神秘
don't worry, we'll come back to this concept again later on.
别担心 稍后我们还会讲解这一概念
For now, it's enough to understand that we've got
暂时只需知道
a block of code that's hidden away somewhere else,
某个其他位置隐藏了一段代码
that this code has a name and now we can run it by using lines
这段代码有个名称 并且现在我们可以使用
like amy.forward100 or amy.right90.
amy.forward(100) 或 amy.right(90) 这样的代码行运行这个代码块